YESENIA ROMÁN

Los Angeles, CA, US ● (939) 207 -8641 romanloyesenia@gmail.com
Website

Dear Hiring Team at Erewhon,

I am writing to apply for the culinary prep cook opening at Erewhon, Culver City.

I have a passion for cooking and previous experience working as a food preparer, and waitress, and over 12 years of experience in customer service in a variety of industries including the retail and education industries. I am also bilingual (Spanish), creative and resourceful.

As a vegetarian and "amateur" gardener, I have great respect and appreciation for the work that goes into growing and preparing something delicious, ethical, and fresh like the food you cook at Erewhon. It never disappoints!

Having worked as a librarian for various years, I am good at working with a team and really enjoy doing my best to achieve something great together, and would love the opportunity to bring this spirit to your kitchen.

Thank you so much for your time and I hope to hear from you soon.

Best regards, Yesenia Román

Relevant experience

General Services Librarian, Part-time Inglewood Public Library, Main Library, Inglewood, CA.

June 2022 - Nov 2022

- ♦ Provided reference services and technological assistance for patrons of all ages.
- Developed and led community programming to engage and educate the public.
- ♦ Curated book displays to showcase the collection.
- Designed promotional materials for programs, events, and social media.

Waitress/Barista

January 2013- Aug. 2013

Restaurante El Nopal, Chicago, IL

- ♦ Welcomed customers and ensured a seamless dining experience.
- ♦ Took customer orders, answered questions about the menu, and suggested dishes per request.
- ♦ Operated an espresso machine to prepare a variety of coffee drinks.

Food preparer

February. 2012 - Oct. 2012

Popcorn Factory, Aguadilla, Puerto Rico

Ensured all protocols and procedures were completed at opening and closing.

- ♦ Prepared a variety of foods including empanadas, hot dogs, chocolate strawberries, and a variety of popcorn flavors.
- ♦ Purchased ingredients for food preparation.
- ♦ Operated an espresso machine to prepare a variety of coffee drinks.

Education

M.S. in Library and Information Sciences, Data Curation specialization University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign

B.A. in Mesoamerican and Caribbean Anthropology University of Puerto Rico, San Juan

Certificate of Training: California Food Handlers Course

Skills

Languages: English (Fluent) • Spanish (Native)
Microsoft Office Excel/Google Sheets
Adobe Illustrator/Procreate/Canvas
Intermediate knowledge of HTML and CSS.
Metadata skills
Project management
Cataloging
Reference
Bibliographic Research
Documentation